# shadmani shaikh

# **UX DESIGNER**

shadmanishaikh.com *𝑉* shadmani@uw.edu 206.499.8873

A UX designer with the unique powers of data analysis and front-end web development. With experiences working in FinTech & Healthcare industries, I bring an engineering perspective and a creative mind to design practical solutions through data-driven research

#### **EDUCATION**

# **University of Washington**

Masters, Human-Centered Design & Engineering

Seattle, WA • 2022 - 2024

# **University of Mumbai**

B.Eng, Computer Engineering

Mumbai, India • 2015 - 2019

### **SKILLS**

## Design

Interaction Design • Storyboarding
Concept Sketching • Wireframing
Rapid Prototyping • Data Visualization

# Research

User Interviews • A/B Testing
Diary Studies • Comparative Analysis
Usability Tests • Surveys • Persona
Hypothesis • Cognitive Walkthrough

# **Tools & Languages**

Python • JavaScript • HTML • CSS
Tableau • Microsoft SQL Server
Sketch • Figma • Adobe CC

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Foundations of User Experience Design 7

IBM Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# General Electric Healthcare | Tata Consultancy Services

UI Developer 2021 - 2022

- Led a team of 5 to redesign a 3-tier enterprise web application for healthcare devices using Angular Material UI (MEAN Stack)
- Drove end-to-end design strategy and user research, collaborating closely with product leaders and executive staff

#### Results & Achievements

- Improved the overall user experience that led to an increased user engagement and a 74% reduction in manual hours
- Received 'Young Achievers Award' for implemented work

# General Electric | Tata Consultancy Services

Tableau Developer 2020 - 2021

- Led design & implementation of interactive dashboards in Tableau for the accounting team
- Designed accounting reports using data visualization to provide structured data from millions of data rows and 12+ data sources
- Collaborated with cross-functional data and accounting teams for improving the efficiency of daily reporting

#### Results & Achievements

 Developed an ETL solution that improved the efficiency of data warehouses by 35%

# MoneyMart | Tata Consultancy Services

BI Data Analyst 2019 - 2020

- Drove key migration from on-prem data warehouse to Microsoft Azure Cloud & built 600+ pipelines & data workflows on Azure Data Factory to support migration
- Developed 50+ ETL packages for data integration & transformation using Microsoft SSIS/SSRS
- Mentored and coached the monitoring team to provide support for production issues

## Results & Achievements

- $\bullet$  Automated ADF data flows that decreased warehouse runtimes by 45%
- · Received 'On the Spot' Award for record-time project delivery